I'm Angie, I'm a Program Manager
of Engineering at Google.
I'm currently working on the
Data Analytics certificate.
Previously, I was a researcher
in people analytics.
I was also what I call
an analytical mercenary
working for a lot of
different companies
to help them make
sense of their data.
Every time I learn a new skill,
I feel like I'm learning how
to speak all over again.
I remember the first
time I learned SQL,
I was so frustrated because
everyone around me,
it felt like they were fluent,
they knew exactly
what they were doing.
I remember struggling with
the most basic things,
just like getting the data out
of the table or I remember
somebody asked me just
to find an average
of something and I kept
on getting an error.
It really does feel like you're
learning a new
language and you're
at toddler level and
everyone around you
is like maybe fluent.
My parents immigrated to
this country when they
are in their 30s.
After they had learned
another language and
they had to start
over and learn English.
I remember as a
child watching them
struggle every day to
pick up a new language,
to do really basic things,
like ask for help at
the grocery store.
I remember calling the cable
company when I was six,
asking them questions about
the bill because my
parents couldn't.
I remember how hard
they worked to
learn this new
language and to become
fluent and every
time I'm learning
a new data language like
SQL or R, I think about how
hard that must have been.
I think if they can do
that, I can learn SQL.
If they can ask for help for
the most basic of things,
I can ask the Data
Analysts next to me how
to write a SQL statement and
how to get data out of a table.
That really helped me,
is just having that mindset
and knowing that I
can ask for help.