Formulas are a
great way to become
more efficient when
using spreadsheets,
especially when you add shortcuts
like copying and
pasting, into the mix.
As you progress as
a data analyst,
you'll most likely learn
more shortcuts to
help your process.
But now it's time to
move on to functions.
While they're closely
related to formulas,
they're not exactly the same.
By the end of this video,
you'll understand
the difference and
know when to use them both.
In the world of spreadsheets
a function is a
preset command that
automatically performs
a specific process
or task using the data.
You might remember
some of the shortcuts
we learned that can be
used with formulas.
Think of functions as the
most useful of the shortcuts.
The good news is a lot of
spreadsheet functions have names
that tell you what they do.
There are tons of
functions out there.
As you continue to work
with spreadsheets,
you'll find that you
use certain ones a lot,
and others, rarely or not at all.
For now, let's take a look
at some of the
functions that we can
apply to our sales data
from the previous video.
We'll start with total sales.
Let's use the SUM function
for this in cell F2.
The first steps are pretty
similar to what we did
in the last video.
First, we'll select the cell
where we want the
calculation to appear.
Type equals, then add the
word SUM as our function.
One of the great
things about functions
is they don't always
need operators,
like a plus sign for addition.
In this case, after
the open parentheses,
you can go ahead and select
the range of cells you're adding.
A colon between the
cell references
shows that you're using a range.
In this case, the range includes
cells from the same row.
After the closed
parentheses, we press Enter.
Just like that, our total
sales number appears.
Just like the formula
we used before,
functions can be
copied and pasted
into other cells in
the same column.
But let's undo that
step so that you can
see another way to copy
a function or formula.
Spreadsheets have something
called a fill handle.
It's a little box that appears in
the lower right-hand corner
when you click on a cell.
If you rest your
cursor on the box,
you can then drag
the fill handle to
the other boxes in the
same row or column.
Any formula or function
in that cell will
automatically be added to
the cells you fill plus,
the fill handle will
update the formula so
the cell references match
the row of the columns
of the cells you fill.
This means the formula
is calculated based
on the data in each
separate row or column.
Filling won't work
for every situation,
but it's still a
pretty great trick.
Now let's find the
average sale for
each month using the
AVERAGE function.
Different functions perform
different calculations,
but they work in the same way.
Keep in mind, not
every calculation
you'll come across has its
own function to help you.
For example, to find
the percent change in sales
between June and July,
you'd use the same formula
you used in an earlier video.
Let's say you're asked to find
the lowest monthly
sales in this data set.
There's a function for that.
It's called the MIN function,
which stands for minimum.
Here's how it works.
Say you need to find the
lowest monthly sales
for the whole set.
All you have to do is
set up the function.
Then after the open parenthesis,
select the values
from all three rows.
This might be
important information
for your stake holders.
Let's add color to the
cell with that value,
in your data set to
make it stand out.
In this case, click on cell
D2 and then fill color icon,
which looks like a paint can,
then choose a color.
I'll use yellow here.
You can follow the same steps for
the highest sales by using the,
wait for it, MAX function.
Looks like we have
an error message.
What could be wrong?
We forgot to include
an open parentheses
after the function.
No worries, it's a quick fix.
But this is a good reminder
to continually check
the format of your functions and
formulas as you use them.
We'll learn more
about Error messages
and how to work with them later.
That's better. Now we'll add
color to the cell with
the highest sales too.
This is just one way
to highlight key data.
You'll find out about
some others later.
You've now had a peek
at some ways you
can add and organize
data in a spreadsheet.
You've also seen how
powerful formulas and
functions can be when
applied to real world data.
As a data analyst,
this is just the beginning of
your experience
with spreadsheets.
You'll soon find out
how much more spreadsheets
have to offer.
In the meantime, you're free to
practice some of these formulas,
functions, and other
processes on your own.
It can be fun to experiment,
and see all that
spreadsheets can do.
Soon, you will switch from
spreadsheets to
structured thinking.
The data analytics pieces are
starting to fit together.
Exciting stuff is coming
right up. So stick around.