Now that you're done,
you're officially
ready to take on the next course.
Awesome job.
But before I tell you
about what's ahead,
let's take a moment to think
about what we've covered so
far in the first step of
the data analysis process.
In this course, we explored
effective questions
and we learned how to use
quantitative and
qualitative data,
metrics and math to
connect the dots.
We also covered
spreadsheet basics,
how to apply structured thinking
and key communication skills for
working with stakeholders and
team members. That's a lot!
Now it's time to take what
you learned into the next course,
where you'll tackle
the next step of
the data analysis process,
prepare your data.
Hallie is going to
take over from here.
You might remember her from
the beginning of
the first course!
She'll guide you as you
learn new important tools
for your work, like data
types and data structures;
bias and credibility
in analytics;
databases;
organizing and
protecting your data;
and the data community.
Thanks for sticking with
me through this course.
When you're ready, you can go
ahead to the first video
in the next course.
Good luck. You're
going to do great.