I'm Nikki and I
manage the education,
evaluation, assessment,
and research team.
My favorite part of the data
analysis process is finding
the hardest problem and asking
a million questions about it and
seeing if it's even
possible to get an answer.
One of the problems that
we've tackled here at
Google is our Noogler
onboarding program,
which is how we
onboard new hires.
One of the things that we've
done is ask the question,
how do we know whether or
not Nooglers are
onboarding faster
through our new
onboarding program than
our old onboarding program
where we used to lecture them.
We worked really closely with
the content providers to
understand just exactly what
does it mean to onboard
someone faster?
Once we asked all the questions,
what we did is we prepared
the data by understanding who was
the population of the new
hires that we were examining.
We prepared our data by going
through and understanding
who our populations were,
by understanding who
our sample set was,
who our control group was,
who our experiment group was,
where were our data sources,
and make sure that it
was in a set, in a format that was
clean and digestible for
us to write the
proper scripts for.
So the next step for us was to
process the data to
make sure that it was
in a format that we could
actually analyze in SQL,
making sure that was
in the right format,
in the right columns,
and in the right tables for us.
To analyze the data,
we wrote scripts in SQL and
in R to correlate the data to
the control group or
the experiment group
and interpret the
data to understand,
were there any changes in
the behavioral
indicators that we saw?
Once we analyze all the data,
we want to report on it in a way
that our stakeholders
could understand.
Depending on who our
stakeholders were,
we prepared reports, dashboards
and presentations, and shared
that information out.
Once all of our
reports were complete,
we saw really positive
results and decided to act on
it by continuing
our project-based learning
onboarding program.
It was really satisfying to
know that we have the data to
support it and that
it really, really worked.
And not just that the data was there,
but that we knew
that our students
were learning and that
they were more productive,
faster back on their jobs.