So far, we've covered the
different roles data
analysts play in
business environments
and the kinds of tasks
that come with those roles.
But data analysts have another
important responsibility:
making sure that their
analyses are fair.
Now, I know what you're
probably thinking,
data is based on
collected facts,
how can it be unfair?
Well, that's a good question.
Let's learn what fairness
means when we talk about
data analysis and why
it's important for
you as an analyst
to keep in mind.
Fairness means ensuring that
your analysis doesn't
create or reinforce bias.
In other words, as
a data analyst,
you want to help create systems
that are fair and
inclusive to everyone.
Sounds simple enough?
Well, here's the tough part
about fairness in
data analytics.
There isn't one standard
definition of it,
but hopefully the way we've
just described it can
give you one way to think
about fairness for right now,
but it's about to
get a bit trickier.
Sometimes conclusions based on
data can be true and unfair.
What can you do then?
Well, let's find out
with an example.
Let's say we have
a company that's
kind of notorious for being a boys club.
There isn't much representation
of other genders.
This company wants to see which
employees are doing well,
so they start gathering data on
employee performance and
their own company culture.
The data shows that men are
the only people succeeding
at this company.
Their conclusion? That they
should hire more men.
After all, they're
doing really well here, right?
But that's not a fair conclusion
for a couple of reasons.
First, it doesn't even consider
all of the available
data on company culture,
so it paints an
incomplete picture.
Second, it doesn't think about
the other surrounding
factors that
impact the data,
or in other words,
the conclusion doesn't consider
the difficulties that people of
different gender identities have
trying to navigate a
toxic work environment.
If the company only looks
at this conclusion,
they won't acknowledge and
address how harmful
their culture is
and they won't understand why
certain people are set
up to fail within it.
That's why it's
important to keep
fairness in mind
when analyzing data.
The conclusion that only men are
succeeding at this
company is true,
but it ignores other
systematic factors
that are contributing
to this problem.
But don't worry, there's
a way to make a fair
conclusion here.
An ethical data analyst
can look at the
data gathered and
conclude that the
company culture is
preventing some employees
from succeeding,
and the company needs to address
those problems to
boost performance.
See how this conclusion paints
a much more complete
and fair picture.
It recognizes the
fact that some people
aren't doing as well in
this company and factors in
why that
could be instead of
discriminating
against a huge number
of applicants in the future.
As a data analyst it's
your responsibility to
make sure your analysis is
fair and factors in
the complicated social context
that could create bias
in your conclusions.
It's important to think about
fairness from the moment
you start collecting
data for a business task to
the time you present
your conclusions to
your stakeholders.
We'll learn more about bias in
the data analysis process
later on in another course.
For now, let's check
out an example of
a data analysis that does
a good job of considering
fairness in its conclusion.
A team of Harvard
data scientists were
developing a mobile
platform to track patients
at risk of cardiovascular
disease in
an area of the United States
called the Stroke Belt.
It's important to call out
that there were a variety of
reasons people living in this
area might be more at risk.
With that in mind,
these data scientists
recognized that
fairness needed to be a
priority for this project,
so they built fairness
into their models.
The team took several
fairness measures
to make sure they
were being as fair
as possible when examining
sensitive and
potentially biased data.
First, they teamed analysts
with social scientists
who could provide
insights on human bias
and the social context
that created them.
They also collected
self reported data in
a separate system to avoid the
potential for racial bias,
which might skew the results of
their study and unfairly
represent patients.
To make sure this sample
population was representative,
they oversampled
non-dominant groups
to ensure the model
was including them.
It's clear that the
team made fairness a
top priority every
step of the way.
This helped them collect data
and create conclusions that
didn't negatively impact
the communities
they were studying.
Hopefully these
examples have given you
a better idea of what fairness
means in data analysis.
But we're going to keep
building on our
understanding of fairness
throughout this program and
you'll get to practice
with some activities.