Hi, I'm Alex. I'm a research
scientist at Google.
My team is called
the ethical AI team,
we're a group of folks that
really are concerned not only
about how AI the
technology operates,
but how it interacts
with society and how it
might help or harm
marginalized communities.
When we talk about data ethics,
we think about what is
the good and right
way of using data?
What are going to be ways that
uses of data are going to
be beneficial to people?
When it comes to data ethics,
it's not just about
minimizing harm but it's
actually this concept
of beneficence.
How do we actually
improve the lives
of people by using data?
When we think about data
ethics we're thinking about,
who's collecting the data?
Why are they collecting it?
How are they collecting
it and for what purpose?
Because of the way that
organizations have
imperatives to make
money or to report to somebody
or provide some analysis,
we also have to keep
strongly in mind
how this is actually going to
benefit people at
the end of the day.
Are the people represented in
this data going to be
benefited by this?
I think that's the
thing you never want to
lose sight of as a data
scientist or a data analyst.
I think aspiring data
analysts need to keep in
mind that a lot of the data that
you're going to encounter is
data that comes from people
so at the end of the
day, data are people.
You want to have a responsibility
to those people that are
represented in those data.
Second, is thinking
about how to keep
aspects of their data
protected and private.
We don't want to go through
our practice thinking
about data instances as
something we can just
throw on the web.
No, there needs to be
considerations about
how to keep that information,
and likenesses like their images,
or their voices, or their text.
How do we keep that private?
We also need to think
about how we can have
mechanisms of giving users
and giving consumers more
control over their data.
It's not going to be
sufficient just to say,
we collect all this data and
trust us with all these data.
But we need to
ensure that there's
actionable ways in which
people can consent to
giving those data,
and ways that they
can ask for it to be
revoked or removed.
Data's growing and
at the same time,
we need to empower people to have
control over their own data.
The future is that data
is always growing,
we haven't seen any evidence
that data is actually shrinking.
With the knowledge
that data's growing,
these issues become
more and more piqued,
and more and more
important to think about.