[MUSIC]
Joining a new team was definitely
scary at the beginning.
Especially at a company like
Google where it's really big and
everyone is extremely smart.
But I really leaned on my manager
to understand what I could bring to
the table.
And that made me feel a lot more
comfortable in meetings while sharing my
abilities.
I found that my best projects start off
when the communication is really clear
about what's expected.
If I leave the meeting
where the project has been
asked of me knowing exactly where
to start and what I need to do,
that allows for me to get it done faster,
more efficiently, and
getting to the real goal of it
and maybe going an extra step further
because I didn't have to spend any time
confused on what I needed to be doing.
Communication is so important because
it gets you to the finish line the most
efficiently and
also makes you look really good.
When I first started I had a good
amount of projects thrown at me and
I was really excited.
So, I went into them without
asking too many questions.
At first that was an obstacle,
because while you can thrive in ambiguity,
ambiguity as to what the project
objective is, can be really harmful
when you're actually trying
to get the goal done.
And I overcame that by simply taking
a step back when someone asks me to do
the project and
just clarifying what that goal was.
Once that goal was crisp,
I was happy to go into
the ambiguity of how to get there,
but the goal has to be really objective and clear.
I'm Ximena and I'm a Financial Analyst.