Your data analysis
toolbox is getting full.
Learning about both
Spreadsheets and
SQL will get you far in the
world of data analysis.
There's more to learn, of course,
and lots more tools
you'll be able to use,
but your future is
looking bright.
It's about to look even brighter,
because we're here to talk
more about data visualization.
I'll tell you a little
more about the role of
data visualization tools
and data analytics,
and give you a chance to see
those tools in action
later in this video.
You might remember that
data visualization
is the graphical
representation of information.
For tons of data analysts,
it's the most exciting part of
their job because they get to
see their hard work pay off
with something interesting.
Not to mention that
data visualization
is beautiful and useful.
I was floored when
I got to Google and
started to get a
quarterly data report in
my e-mail and had
a big slide deck where
people contributed
their visualizations.
It was definitely a
source of light as I
started to build my
own visualizations.
If you're not
impressed by my story,
let me tell you about
Florence Nightingale.
Does that name ring a bell?
She is responsible for much of
the philosophy of modern nursing,
and believe it or not,
she was also a data analyst.
During the Crimean
War in the 1850s,
thousands of soldiers
were dying every day,
Nightingale wanted to find a way
to reduce the number of deaths.
After examining the data,
she found that the majority of
soldiers were dying from
preventable conditions.
To convince hospital
administrators
that they needed to focus
on these conditions,
she created a chart showing
the number of deaths
over several months.
The much larger blue sections in
the visualization represent
the preventable deaths.
Her work directly led to major
changes in patient care.
She did all of this over
150 years ago without a computer.
One of the main reasons
Nightingale created
this visualization was to make
the data easier to
digest for her audience.
She felt she'd be more
successful convincing
the stakeholders
using visuals instead of
just words and numbers.
She was right, tables
filled with data,
while necessary for analysis,
just aren't able to show
trends and patterns as
quickly and clearly as
visualizations can.
Imagine, you receive
an assignment that
needs to be completed
the same day.
You gather the data
you need in a table,
could you explain your
findings using the table?
Yes, you probably could,
but a better idea will be to use
a visualization like
this bar graph.
Something like this makes it much
easier for you to
explain quickly,
and you've got the benefit of
a cool graphic to
backup your analysis.
As a data analyst,
you'll want to create
visualizations that
make the data easy to understand,
and interesting to look
at, so show it off.
Stakeholders may not have
much time to devote to the data,
your job will be to make
their time worthwhile.
Let's go back to
that data table we
created earlier in the course.
If you created your
own for practice,
you can open it up now
or try this out later.
Here's the data we added before.
Let's create a
visualization of the data
by inserting a
chart, a bar graph.
You can see that the
spreadsheet visualized
the data from our table in
a way that made the most sense.
It created a bar graph or
column chart to compare the
ages of each person by name,
but you might have
figured that out already.
That's the beauty
of visualization,
it shows data analysis
quickly and clearly.
We can use chart editor
to adjust the chart.
Different spreadsheet
programs might
have different ways to do this,
but they all have
visualization functions
and ways to edit
those visualizations.
For now, let's just look
at the suggested charts.
We can make the bars go
horizontally using a bar chart.
That looks great, so let's
close the Chart editor.
There are lots of
options to look at,
but we'll keep it basic for now.
Feel free to try
other visualizations
if you practice later.
Now, we can adjust
our chart to make
our whole spreadsheet look
clean and professional.
Excellent. I hope
you learn to love
data visualization
as much as I do.
Maybe you'll become a data
visualization pioneer,
just like Florence Nightingale.
As a budding data analysts,
you started to fill
your utility belt with
valuable tools that you'll
use throughout the
rest of the program.
Having spreadsheets, SQL
and data visualization
know-how will help make
you an ace data detective.
You'll be able to use
these tools throughout
the data analytics process
as you move forward.
Coming up next, you complete
a few activities to wrap up
this part of the program.
You'll also complete
an assessment to
check your understanding
of all that you learn.
This is a great opportunity to
think about some
of the areas that
you'll continue to explore
in this course and
in your career.
As always, feel free to
review the videos and
readings to help remind you
of certain topics and ideas,
even if you already
feel prepared.
You're just a few steps
away from the next course,
that's great
progress. Keep it up.