[MUSIC]
My name is Lilah Jones, and
I am a part of our cloud team.
I get a chance to lead a team of amazing
individuals that are focused on helping
customers get to the cloud.
Data visualizations,
that's a long word and
that can also make your eyes glaze over.
But I wonder if, when you were little and
you were with your parents,
maybe they had a bedtime routine or
maybe you have children,
you're doing a bedtime routine with them.
You very rarely are going to come to
those children with a bunch of facts and
figures before they go to bed.
But I bet you probably are telling them
a story, you're showing them pictures,
I know I always loved comic books,
pictures tell a story.
Data visualizations are pictures,
they are a wonderful way to take
very basic ideas around data and
data points and make them come alive.
You can do all different types of
combinations of visualizations,
but the ones that are interactive,
wow, those are huge.
Can you imagine being executive of an
organization and
trying to figure out how
should we open up another site in Bangkok?
Does that make sense and
us being able to walk in and saying,
here's why it makes sense in having
great data visualizations to support all
of our points of view,
makes it a no brainer.
Interestingly enough, I do recall
the first time I came across a super
amazing visualization,
it was in my personal life.
I switched my budgeting software
from one provider to another, and
the provider that I switched to was really
focused on every dollar has a job and
making sure you're budgeting,
every single dollar.
They gave visualizations that change,
depending on what input you would add
to it and it really just changed my
entire perspective, the entire thing.
So having the data is like having
the answer sheet for a test,
it really just lets you know that you're
going to make good decisions because it's
backed up by data.