In a previous video,
I shared how data
analysis helped a company
figure out where to
advertise its services.
An important part
of this process
was strong
problem-solving skills.
As a data analyst,
you'll find that problems
are at the center
of what you do every single day,
but that's a good thing.
Think of problems as opportunities
to put your skills to
work and find creative
and insightful solutions.
Problems can be small or large,
simple or complex,
no problem is like another
and they all require
a slightly different approach
but the first step
is always the same:
Understanding what kind of
problem you're trying to
solve and that's what we're
going to talk about now.
Data analysts work with
a variety of problems.
In this video, we're going to
focus on six common types.
These include: making
predictions, categorizing things,
spotting something unusual,
identifying themes,
discovering connections,
and finding patterns.
Let's define each of these now.
First, making predictions.
This problem type involves
using data to make
an informed decision about
how things may be in the future.
For example, a hospital
system might use
a remote patient monitoring to
predict health events for
chronically ill patients.
The patients would take
their health vitals
at home every day,
and that information combined
with data about their age,
risk factors, and other
important details could enable
the hospital's
algorithm to predict
future health problems and
even reduce future
hospitalizations.
The next problem type
is categorizing things.
This means assigning
information to
different groups or clusters
based on common features.
An example of this
problem type is
a manufacturer that
reviews data on
shop floor employee performance.
An analyst may create
a group for employees
who are most and least
effective at engineering.
A group for employees
who are most and least
effective at repair
and maintenance,
most and least
effective at assembly,
and many more
groups or clusters.
Next, we have spotting
something unusual.
In this problem type,
data analysts identify data
that is different from the norm.
An instance of
spotting something
unusual in the real world is
a school system that has
a sudden increase in the
number of students registered,
maybe as big as
a 30 percent jump in
the number of students.
A data analyst might look into
this upswing and discover that
several new apartment
complexes had been
built in the school
district earlier that year.
They could use this analysis
to make sure the school has
enough resources to handle
the additional students.
Identifying themes is
the next problem type.
Identifying themes takes
categorization as a step
further by grouping information
into broader concepts.
Going back to our
manufacturer that has just
reviewed data on the
shop floor employees.
First, these people are
grouped by types and tasks.
But now a data analyst could
take those categories
and group them into
the broader concept of
low productivity and
high productivity.
This would make it possible
for the business to
see who is most and
least productive,
in order to reward
top performers and
provide additional support to
those workers who
need more training.
Now, the problem type of
discovering connections enables
data analysts to find
similar challenges faced
by different entities,
and then combine data and
insights to address them.
Here's what I mean;
say a scooter company
is experiencing
an issue with the wheels it
gets from its wheel supplier.
That company would have to
stop production until it could
get safe, quality
wheels back in stock.
But meanwhile, the wheel
companies encountering
the problem with the rubber
it uses to make wheels,
turns out its rubber
supplier could
not find the right
materials either.
If all of these entities
could talk about
the problems they're facing
and share data openly,
they would find a lot of
similar challenges
and better yet,
be able to collaborate
to find a solution.
The final problem type
is finding patterns.
Data analysts use data to find
patterns by using
historical data to
understand what happened in
the past and is therefore
likely to happen again.
Ecommerce companies use data to
find patterns all the time.
Data analysts look at
transaction data to understand
customer buying habits at
certain points in time
throughout the year.
They may find that
customers buy more
canned goods right
before a hurricane,
or they purchase fewer
cold-weather accessories
like hats and gloves
during warmer months.
The ecommerce companies can
use these insights to make sure
they stock the right amount of
products at these key times.
Alright, you've now learned six
basic problem types
that data analysts
typically face.
As a future data analyst,
this is going to be valuable
knowledge for your career.
Coming up, we'll talk a bit more
about these problem
types and I'll
provide even more
examples of them
being solved by data analysts.
Personally, I love
real-world examples.
They really help me better
understand new concepts.
I can't wait to share
even more actual cases
with you. See you there.