Hi, I'm Anmol.
I'm the Head of Large
Advertiser Marketing Analytics
within the Marketing
Team at Google.
At its core, my job
is about connecting
the right user with the right
message at the right time.
The first step is really to get
a broad sense of the certain
pattern that's occurring.
So for example, we know that
this particular segment
of users is more responsive
to this type of content.
Once we're able to actually see
this hypothesis through the data,
we do testing to ensure
that the hypothesis
is actually correct.
So for example, we would test
sending these pieces of content
to this segment of users,
and actually verify within
a controlled environment
whether that response rate is
actually higher for
that type of content,
or whether it isn't.
Once we're able to actually
verify that hypothesis,
we go back to the stakeholders,
in this case, our
marketers, and say,
we've proven within a relatively
high degree of certainty
that this particular
segment is more
responsive to this type of
content, and because of that,
we're recommending that you
produce more of this
type of content.
Our stakeholders
really get to see
the whole evolution from
hypothesis to proven concept,
and they're able to
come with us on the journey
on how we're proving out
these hypotheses and then
eventually turning them
into strategies and
recommendations for the business.
The outcome in this
case was that we
were able to actually change the way
our whole marketing team worked
to actually make it
much more user-centric.
Instead of, from our perspective,
coming up with content that
we think the users need,
we're actually going in
the other direction of
figuring out what
users need first,
proving that they need
certain things or they
don't need certain things,
and then using that information
going back to marketers
and coming up with content
that fulfills their need.
So it really changed
the direction of
how we produce things.