Hey, great to have you back.
Now it's time to get down to business.
We're going to start talking about
practical ways businesses are using data,
and the opportunities that
it can create for you.
So far, you've learned a lot of
practical data analysis skills.
With these next couple of videos,
we're going to switch gears a little and
talk about why you're
learning these skills.
Hopefully this will give you more
perspective into what kinds of
opportunities are out there for you.
Coming up, we're going to talk more
about the kinds of roles data analysts
play in different industries.
The task that these roles required,
and the importance of fairness and
avoiding bias and
analyzing data for business tasks.
We'll also talk about
opportunities you can tap into, and
how this program factors into your future
success and the data analyst role.
So with all that in mind,
let's get started.