Hi, I'm Joey and I work as an analytics
program manager within REWS.
Now REWS stands for real estate and
workplace services, and
my job is to bring data and
analytics into the decision-making here,
especially with regards to creating
a safe and fun work environment.
My journey into analytics was a bit
different in that I had no plan or
really didn't see myself
being where I am now. Now
luckily, I started in a rotational program
called the HRA program within people
operations, which afforded me the ability
to play three different roles essentially.
I was in a generalist capacity in
a specialist role and as an analyst,
and I really found a love and
a passion in the analytical work.
I started on the business
intelligence team,
whose job was to provide SQL-based
reporting back to the business.
I realized the analytics is
the right career path for
me when I found myself enjoying coming
to work and getting my work done.
And I think I can connect
that to two passions of mine.
The first is problem-solving.
I love taking a complex problem,
a mystery, a riddle and being able to find
the answers and come up with the solution.
And then the second thing is being able
to work with people and help people.
In analytics I feel like the key
to success is being able to blend
the personal side with the technical side.
At the beginning of my career, I focused
a little more on the technical pieces, and
I wanted to make sure I had the right
technical knowledge to be able to answer
questions.
But what I found is over time I needed
to grow that other side just as much.
And I think that my career has allowed
me those opportunities to kind of
work each of those muscles, the human
interaction part and the technical part
to make sure that they're both
growing at the end of the day.