"Data! Data! Data! I can't
make bricks without clay."
Any guesses who said this?
I'll give you a hint.
It wasn't a famous tech CEO,
or a data analyst.
The person who said this lived
long before the tech
companies even existed.
But I bet you've
still heard of him.
This line was said
by Sherlock Holmes,
the famous detective created
by Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.
What Doyle meant was that
Holmes couldn't draw
any conclusions,
which would be the
bricks he mentioned
without data, or the clay.
You're probably
not here to become
a world famous detective,
but data is still the building
block that you'll use
for everything you do in your
new data analyst career,
Sherlock Holmes would agree.
By starting this program,
you've shown that you and
Sherlock Holmes have
something in common,
you both have an interest
in learning more.
That's one of the most
important qualities
that data analysts can have.
Now, there are a bunch of
different ways to explore data,
but one of the great things
about data analytics is that
you can often learn how
you want, when you want.
That might mean doing
your own research,
talking with people
in the industry,
or taking online courses.
With that said, welcome
to your first course.
This is your introduction to
the wonderful world
of data analytics.
Since data analytics is
the science of data,
you'll use this course to
begin to learn all about data.
Data is basically a
collection of facts
or information, and
through analysis,
you'll learn how to use the
data to draw conclusions,
and make predictions,
and decisions.
Personally, I didn't jump
right into the data
analytics field.
I thought data analysis was
for computer engineers.
Instead, I started off with
dreams of working in finance.
Once I got through an
internship though,
I realized it wasn't the
career path I wanted to take.
I started to learn about
financial planning and analysis,
and all of the work
finance analysts were
doing with data.
I realized that finance
analysts are really
just data analysts working
in a finance department.
These analysts were
helping to guide
business decisions by
knowing how to use data.
It was then I realized
how powerful data is,
and I started to embrace it.
Soon enough, I realized I could
do this data analysis myself.
Data analytics is a big
open world of opportunity.
There are so many areas that
your analysis skills can be
applied and in all
different ways.
If you're new to this world,
you'll learn how to
identify which path and
industry might suit your skills,
and your interests the best.
For those of you who already
have some experience,
we'll help you open doors
to new and exciting
opportunities.
One of the skills
you'll gain from
the program is how to follow
the best practices that analysts
use to help make
data-driven decisions.
Computers are one
part of the process,
but analysts rely on so much
more to make decisions.
That's why learning how
to think analytically,
and using your other
skills and traits
on the job will make
your work easier.
I know you already know how
to make good decisions,
you chose to be here after all.
In this first course,
you'll learn more
about each phase
of the data analysis process.
Ask, prepare, process,
analyze, share, and act.
As a data analyst,
you'll go through
these steps as you
use data to inform
your decisions.
Eventually, you'll see how
this program itself is in a way,
its own version of this process.
While I know you'll enjoy
watching these videos,
your trip to the first course
will include a whole lot more.
Other videos will take
the form of vignettes,
where you'll learn from data
analytics professionals,
who are already established
in their careers.
They'll offer words of
wisdom as well as tales of
their own experiences starting
off on their career path.
You'll start your own data
journal that will help
you keep track of what you've
learned throughout the course.
You'll also add your own
thoughts about what you're
learning as well,
throughout the program.
You'll read up on how to navigate
this program in the
world of data analytics.
You'll complete
activities, including some
that will help you get in the
mindset of a data analyst.
Along the way, you'll also have
the chance to connect with
your fellow learners.
Discussion prompts will give you
a chance to share your thoughts,
and at the same time see
what your peers think about
all that you're learning.
These prompts will help you build
a community support system to
use throughout the program.
Enough talking, let's get
started on this exciting path.
Your next step awaits.