Welcome back. In the
next few videos,
you'll continue to explore
the data analytics tools
we discussed earlier,
and you'll get the chance to see
them in action a little bit.
This will give you
a clearer picture
of how to use these tools.
The rest of the program will
build on from what
you learn here.
We'll start with a closer
look at spreadsheets.
We'll break spreadsheets
down to their basics to
better understand a few of
their features and functions.
You'll also learn how
you might want to use
them in your work
as a data analyst.
For example, how do you
sort data to make
it easier to use?
We'll find out. Next, we'll see
SQL in action. Data analysts
use SQL in their
work all the time.
Like when they need a
large amount of data in
seconds to help answer a
quick business question.
Chances are, you're not
familiar with SQL. That's okay.
You'll learn how using
SQL is just like
ordering food at a super
speedy restaurant.
Your SQL query might not be as
delicious but you won't
have to wait long
to get your order.
Speaking of food, what
better topic than dessert?
You can think of data
visualization as
the dessert to the meal
of data analytics.
It's served at the end of
your analysis after
you've done what you
need to get the right data
for a question or task.
We've already seen that
visualizations come
in a lot of forms,
like graphs or charts.
Just like dessert, they're
a treat to look at.
You'll learn more about
these visual representations
and see other examples
of how they might look.
Then you'll get to talk
about visualizations
with other future data
analysts just like yourself.
We'll wrap things up
with an assessment,
but you'll have time to
review what you've
learned before then.
Okay, let's keep going.
By the way, is anyone
else hungry now?