We've covered a lot.
I'm sure you have so
much to think about already.
That's a good thing.
It means you've started
collecting data and
you're doing your own
personal analysis.
That's what it's all about.
You've built a
great base already.
As this course continues,
your knowledge and
data analysis skills
will continue to grow.
Once you've established
a solid foundation,
you'll apply what you've learned
to the rest of the program.
The data analysis
process will help
provide a framework
for everything you do.
Soon, you'll take your
first graded assessment.
It's a great way to check
your understanding of
the concepts and build
confidence in your knowledge.
Everyone learns at
different speeds.
So take your time.
Get familiar with the concepts.
As soon as you feel ready,
you can go ahead and get started.
Keep in mind, if at any point,
you're not sure about a question,
you can always review
the videos and
readings to remind
yourself of the answer.
We're all about open-
book tests here.
Once you've passed, you'll
be all set to move on.
You've got this.
Before you know it,
you'll be done with all
of the courses, and you'll
be ready to create
your own case study.
Then, if it's what
you want to do,
you'll start your job search,
equipped with the
tools and skills
that will wow any
company you talk to.
I can't wait to see where
you go with data analytics.
For now though, give
yourself a pat on the back
for a job well
done. See you soon.