In an earlier video, you learned about
five essential analytical skills.
As a reminder, they're curiosity,
understanding context,
having a technical mindset,
data design, and data strategy.
In the next couple of videos,
we'll explore how these
abilities all become part of
data-driven decision-making.
But first, let's look at the concept
of data-driven decision-making and
why it's more likely to lead
to successful outcomes.
You might remember that data-driven
decision-making involved using facts to
guide business strategy.
Data analysts can tap into the power of
data to do all kinds of amazing things.
With data, they can gain valuable
insights, verify their theories or
assumptions, better
understand opportunities and
challenges, support an objective,
help make a plan, and much more.
In business,
data-driven decision-making can improve
the results in a lot of different ways.
For example, say a dairy farmer wants
to start making and selling ice cream.
They could guess what flavors
customers would like, but
there's a better way to
get the information.
The farmer could survey people and
ask them what flavors they prefer.
This gives the farmer the data they need
to pick ice cream flavors people will
enjoy.
Here's another example.
Let's say the president of an organization
is curious about what perks employees
value most.
She asked the human resources director
who says people value casual dress code.
It's a gut feeling, but the HR director
backs it up with the fact that he sees
a lot of people wearing jeans and
t-shirts.
But what if this company were to use a
more structured employee feedback process,
such as a survey?
It might reveal that employees actually
enjoy free public transportation
cards the most.
The human resources director just didn't
realize that because he drives to work.
These are just some of the benefits
of data-driven decision-making.
It gives you greater confidence
about your choice and
your abilities to address
business challenges.
It helps you become more proactive when
an opportunity presents itself, and
it saves you time and
effort when working towards a goal.
Now let's learn more about how these five
skills help you tap into all the potential
of data-driven decision-making.
First, think about curiosity and context.
The more you learn about
the power of data,
the more curious you're likely to become.
You'll start to see patterns and
relationships in everyday life,
whether you're reading the news,
watching a movie, or
going to an appointment across town.
The analysts take their thinking
a step further by using context to make
predictions, research answers, and
eventually draw conclusions
about what they've discovered.
This natural process is a great first
step in becoming more data-driven.
Having a technical mindset comes next.
Everyone has instincts, or
as in the case of our human resources
director example, gut feelings.
Data analysts are no different.
They have gut feelings too.
But they've trained themselves
to build on those feelings and
use a more technical
approach to explore them.
They do this by always seeking out
the facts, putting them to work through
analysis, and using the insights they
gain to make informed decisions.
Next, we come to data design,
which has a strong connection
to data-driven decision-making.
To put it simply, designing your data so
that it is organized in a logical way makes
it easy for data analysts to access,
understand, and
make the most of available information.
And it's important to keep in mind
that data design doesn't just apply to
databases.
This kind of thinking can work with
all sorts of real-life situations too.
The basic idea is this.
If you make decisions that
are informed by data,
you are more likely to make more
informed and effective decisions.
The final ability is data strategy, which
incorporates the people, processes, and
tools used to solve a problem.
This is a big one to remember because data
strategy gives you a high-level view of
the path you need to take
to achieve your goals.
Also, data-driven decision-making
isn't a one-person job.
It's much more likely to be successful if
everyone is on board and on the same page,
so it's important to make sure
specific procedures are in place and
that your technology being used is
aligned with your data-driven strategy.
Now you know how these five essential
analytical skills work towards making
better, data-driven decisions.
So far, many of the examples
you've heard are hypothetical.
That means they could be true in theory,
but aren't specific real-world cases.
Next, we'll look at some real examples.
I can't wait to share how data analysts
put data to work for amazing results.