Hey, welcome back.
So far you've learned about
things like spreadsheets,
analytical thinking skills,
metrics, and mathematics.
These are all super
important technical skills
that you'll build on throughout
your Data Analytics career.
You should also keep in mind that
there are some
non-technical skills that
you can use to create
a positive and productive
working environment.
These skills will help
you consider the way you
interact with your colleagues
as well as your stakeholders.
We already know that
it's important to keep
your team members' and
stakeholders' needs in mind.
Coming up, we'll talk
about why that is.
We'll start learning
some communication
best practices you can use
in your day to day work.
Remember, communication is key.
We'll start by learning
all about effective
communication,
and how to balance team
member and stakeholder needs.
Think of these
skills as new tools
that'll help you work
with your team to
find the best possible solutions.
Alright, let's head on to the next
video and get started.