As a data analyst,
you'll be required to focus
on a lot of different things,
And your stakeholders'
expectations are
one of the most important.
We're going to talk about why
stakeholder expectations
are so important to
your work and look at
some examples of stakeholder
needs on a project.
By now you've heard me use
the term stakeholder a lot.
So let's refresh ourselves
on what a stakeholder is.
Stakeholders are people that
have invested time, interest,
and resources into
the projects that
you'll be working on
as a data analyst.
In other words, they hold
stakes in what you're doing.
There's a good
chance they'll need
the work you do to
perform their own needs.
That's why it's so
important to make
sure your work lines
up with their needs
and why you need to communicate
effectively with all of
the stakeholders
across your team.
Your stakeholders will want to
discuss things like
the project objective,
what you need to reach that goal,
and any challenges or
concerns you have.
This is a good thing.
These conversations help build
trust and confidence
in your work.
Here's an example of
a project with
multiple team members.
Let's explore what
they might need from
you at different levels to
reach the project's goal.
Imagine you're a data
analyst working with
a company's human
resources department.
The company has experienced
an increase in its turnover rate,
which is the rate at which
employees leave a company.
The company's HR department
wants to know why that
is and they want you to help them
figure out potential solutions.
The Vice President of
HR at this company is
interested in identifying
any shared patterns
across employees who quit
and seeing if there's
a connection to employee
productivity and engagement.
As a data analyst,
it's your job to focus on
the HR department's question and
help find them an answer.
But the VP might be
too busy to manage
day-to-day tasks or might
not be your direct contact.
For this task, you'll be updating
the project manager
more regularly.
Project managers are in charge of
planning and executing a project.
Part of the project manager's
job is keeping the project
on track and overseeing the
progress of the entire team.
In most cases, you'll need to
give them regular updates,
let them know what you
need to succeed and
tell them if you have any
problems along the way.
You might also be working
with other team members.
For example, HR administrators
will need to know
the metrics you're
using so that they
can design ways
to effectively gather
employee data.
You might even be working with
other data analysts who are
covering different
aspects of the data.
It's so important
that you know who
the stakeholders and
other team members are in
a project so that you can
communicate with
them effectively and
give them what they need to move
forward in their own
roles on the project.
You're all working
together to give
the company vital insights
into this problem.
Back to our example.
By analyzing company data,
you see a decrease in
employee engagement and
performance after their first
13 months at the company,
which could mean that employees
started feeling demotivated or
disconnected from their work
and then often quit
a few months later.
Another analyst who focuses on
hiring data also shares that
the company had a large increase
in hiring around 18 months ago.
You communicate this information
with all your team members and
stakeholders and they provide
feedback on how to share this
information with your VP.
In the end, your VP decides
to implement an in-depth
manager check-in with
employees who are
about to hit their 12
month mark at the firm
to identify career growth
opportunities, which
reduces the employee turnover
starting at the
13 month mark.
This is just one example
of how you might
balance needs and expectations
across your team.
You'll find that in
pretty much every project
you work on as a data analyst,
different people on your team,
from the VP of HR to your
fellow data analysts,
will need all your focus and
communication to carry
the project to success.
Focusing on stakeholder
expectations
will help you understand
the goal of a project,
communicate more effectively
across your team,
and build trust in your work.
Coming up, we'll discuss how to
figure out where you
fit on your team
and how you can
help move a project
forward with focus
and determination.