So now that we know the
importance of finding
the balance across
your stakeholders
and your team members.
I want to talk about
the importance of
staying focused on the objective.
This can be tricky when you find
yourself working
with a lot of people
with competing needs
and opinions. But by
asking yourself a
few simple questions
at the beginning of each task,
you can ensure that
you're able to stay focused on
your objective while still
balancing stakeholder needs.
Let's think about our
employee turnover example
from the last video.
There, we were
dealing with a lot of
different team members and
stakeholders like managers,
administrators, even
other analysts.
As a data analyst,
you'll find that
balancing everyone's needs
can be a little chaotic sometimes
but part of your
job is to look past
the clutter and stay
focused on the objective.
It's important to concentrate on
what matters and
not get distracted.
As a data analyst,
you could be working on
multiple projects with lots of
different people but no matter
what project you're working on,
there are three things you can
focus on that will
help you stay on task.
One, who are the primary
and secondary stakeholders?
Two who is managing the data?
And three where can you go for help?
Let's see if we can apply
those questions to
our example project.
The first question you can ask is
about who those stakeholders are.
The primary stakeholder of
this project is probably
the Vice President of
HR who's hoping to use
his project's findings to make
new decisions about
company policy.
You'd also be giving updates to
your project manager,
team members,
or other data analysts who are
depending on your work
for their own task.
These are your
secondary stakeholders.
Take time at the beginning
of every project to
identify your stakeholders
and their goals.
Then see who else is on your team
and what their roles are.
Next, you'll want to ask
who's managing the data?
For example, think about
working with other
analysts on this project.
You're all data analysts,
but you may manage different
data within your project.
In our example, there
was another data analyst
who was focused on managing
the company's hiring data.
Their insights around
a surge of new hires
18 months ago turned out to
be a key part of your analysis.
If you hadn't communicated
with this person,
you might have spent
a lot of time trying
to collect or analyze hiring data
yourself or you may not have
even been able to include
it in your analysis at all.
Instead, you were able
to communicate your
objectives with
another data analyst and use
existing work to make
your analysis richer.
By understanding who's
managing the data,
you can spend your time
more productively.
Next step, you need to know
where you can go
when you need help.
This is something
you should know at
the beginning of any
project you work on.
If you run into bumps in
the road on your way
to completing a task,
you need someone who is best
positioned to take down
those barriers for you.
When you know who's able to help,
you'll spend less time worrying
about other aspects of
the project and more time
focused on the objective.
So who could you go to if you
ran into a problem
on this project?
Project managers support you and
your work by managing
the project timeline,
providing guidance and resources,
and setting up
efficient workflows.
They have a big picture
view of the project
because they know what you
and the rest of the
team are doing.
This makes them a great resource
if you run into a problem
in the employee turnover example,
you would need to
be able to access
employee departure survey data
to include in your analysis.
If you're having trouble getting
approvals for that access,
you can speak with your
project manager to remove
those barriers for
you so that you
can move forward
with your project.
Your team depends on you to stay
focused on your task
so that as a team,
you can find solutions.
By asking yourself
three easy questions
at the beginning of new projects,
you'll be able to address
stakeholder needs,
feel confident about who is
managing the data, and get
help when you need it so that
you can keep your
eyes on the prize:
the project objective. So far
we've covered the importance
of working effectively on
a team while maintaining your
focus on stakeholder needs.
Coming up, we'll go over some
practical ways to become
better communicators
so that we can
help make sure the team
reaches its goals.