Welcome.
Now that you have
a solid foundation
on the basics of data,
it's time to focus on some
particular skills and
characteristics that will be key
to your future career
as a data analyst.
We'll begin with five key skills,
move on to the characteristics
of analytical thinking and then
learn how data analysts
balance their roles
and responsibilities.
Along the way, you'll
also discover how to
tap into your own natural
abilities for strategy,
technical expertise,
and data design.
These are incredibly
helpful skills to
have and you'll learn how
to make them even stronger.
Finally, you'll be introduced to
some fascinating
real-world examples of how
data is influencing the lives
of people all around the world.
All right. Let's get started.