By now, we know that
there are all kinds of
jobs in different industries
available for data analysts.
But now it's time to think
about something
just as important,
how can you tell if a
job is a good fit for
you and your career
goals? Tough one.
Don't worry, that's exactly what
we'll cover in this video.
There's a lot of
important factors to
think about when searching
for your dream job.
Let's talk about some of the
most common factors first,
industry, tools, location,
travel, and culture.
Data is already being used by
countless industries in all
kinds of different ways,
tech, marketing,
finance, health care,
the list goes on.
But one thing that's
important to keep in mind,
every industry has
specific data needs
that have to be addressed
differently by their
data analysts.
The same revenue
data can be used in
three different ways by
data analysts in three
different industries,
financial services,
Telecom, and tech.
For example, a finance analyst at
a bank post public
revenue data of
Telecom company X to
create a forecast that
predicts where
revenues will be in
the future to recommend
the stock price.
The business analyst
at Telecom company X
uses that same data to
advise the sales team.
Then a data analyst
at the company
who created a customer
management tool for
Telecom company X will use that
revenue data to determine how
efficiently the
software is performing.
Finance, telecom, and tech,
all use data differently,
so they need analysts who
have different skills.
It all comes down to what the
needs of the industry are.
Those needs will determine
what task you'll be given,
the questions you'll
be answering and
even how you'll
approach job searching.
If you're just starting out,
a great way to guide
your search is to
think first about what
you're interested in.
Does helping people get
healthier sound
meaningful to you?
Maybe you want to focus on using
data to improve
hospital admissions.
What about helping people
save for a happy retirement?
You might want a job
that uses data to
determine risk factors in
financial investments.
Or maybe you're
interested in helping
journalism grow in your city.
A job using data to help find
your local news website find
more subscribers could be
the perfect role for you.
The key is to think about
your interests early
in your job search.
That'll lead you in
the right direction,
and it will help you
in interviews too.
Potential employers
will want to know
why you're interested
in their company,
and how you can
address their needs,
so if you can speak about
your motivation to work in
data analytics during interviews,
you'll make yourself
stand out in a great way.
You'll have options
when it comes to
where you work and
who you work for.
But remember, you want
to enjoy what you do,
so it's a good idea to think
about how you want
to use your skills.
Then search for jobs that
allow you to do that.
Next on the list
of things to think
about, location and travel.
When you start your job search,
you need to make some decisions
about where you want to live,
so it helps to ask
yourself some questions,
does your preferred industry have
opportunities in your area?
Are you trying to stay local
or would you be happy relocating?
How long are you willing to
commute to work every day?
Will you drive to work,
walk, take public transport?
Is that possible year-round?
How do you feel about
working remotely?
Does working from home
excite you or bore you?
Of course, you'll want to
consider cost of living,
and whether or not you want
the convenience of city living
or a quiet suburban home,
and it's not just about
where you'll be based,
some jobs may ask you to travel,
which could be an
exciting chance to see
the world or a deal-breaker.
It's all about what you
want out of this job,
so start asking yourself
some of these questions.
Figuring out the
answers can help you
narrow down your
search even further,
so you're only looking at
jobs you'd actually accept.
Once you've answered
enough questions,
you'll be able to identify
some specific companies
that fit your needs.
At this point, it's a
good time to think about
your values and what
company culture is
a good fit for you.
Ready, here comes
some more questions,
do you work best in a
team or by yourself?
Do you like to have a
set routine or do you
enjoy taking a new project
and trying new things?
Do your values match
the company's values?
You'll want to pay attention
to these things during
your job search and
interview process,
so you can be sure you fully
invested in the
company you work for.
That's the best way
to start building
an exciting and
fulfilling career.
This program will help you learn
the core skills for data
analytics in any setting,
it's up to you where
you want to take them,
whether that means starting
in a completely new industry,
or moving into an
analyst position in
an industry you already
have experience in.
Hopefully what we've
covered here has helped
you get on track for
your future job search.
After this, you have a
few activities to do,
and then you'll be
able to move on to
the next part of this course.
We learned a lot so far,
like what opportunities
are out there
for data analysts in
different industries.
How data analysts help businesses
make better decisions.
The importance of fairness
and data analytics,
and the potential
questions you can start
asking yourself before
your future job search,
and you can always look back at
these lessons if
you want to review.
In an upcoming course,
we'll look at the skills all
successful data analysts
have and you'll learn how
you can start
practicing them too.
But before that, you'll
have an assessment.
Good luck, and I'll
see you later.