Now that you understand
all the phases of
the data life cycle,
it's time to move on to the
phases of data analysis.
They sound similar, but
are two different things.
Data analysis isn't a life cycle.
It's the process
of analyzing data.
Coming up, we'll
look at each step of
the data analysis process and how
it will relate to your
work as a data analyst.
Even this program is designed
to follow these steps.
Understanding these
connections will help guide
your own analysis and your
work in this program.
You've already learned that
this program is modeled
after the stages of the
data analysis process.
This program is
split into courses,
six of which are based upon
the steps of data analysis:
ask, prepare, process,
analyze, share, and act.
Let's start with
the first step in
data analysis, the ask phase.
In this phase, we do two things.
We define the problem to
be solved and we make
sure that we fully understand
stakeholder expectations.
Stakeholders hold a
stake in the project.
They are people who have
invested time and resources into
a project and are interested
in the outcome. Let's
break that down.
First, defining a problem
means you look at
the current state and identify
how it's different
from the ideal state.
Usually there's an obstacle
we need to get rid
of or something wrong
that needs to be fixed.
For instance, a sports
arena might want to
reduce the time fans spend
waiting in the ticket line.
The obstacle is
figuring out how to get
the customers to their
seats more quickly.
Another important
part of the ask phase
is understanding
stakeholder expectations.
The first step here is to
determine who the
stakeholders are.
That may include your manager,
an executive sponsor,
or your sales partners.
There can be lots
of stakeholders.
But what they all have in
common is that they
help make decisions,
influence actions and strategies,
and have specific goals
they want to meet.
They also care about the
project and that's why
it's so important to
understand their expectations.
For instance, if your
manager assigns you
a data analysis project
related to business risk,
it would be smart to confirm
whether they want to
include all types of risks
that could affect the company,
or just risks related to
weather such as
hurricanes and tornadoes.
Communicating with your
stakeholders is key in making
sure you stay engaged
and on track throughout
the project.
So as a data analyst,
developing strong
communication strategies
is very important.
This part of the ask phase helps
you keep focused on
the problem itself,
not just its symptoms.
As you learned earlier,
the five whys are
extremely helpful here.
In an upcoming course,
you'll learn how to ask
effective questions
and define the problem by
working with stakeholders.
You'll also cover strategies
that can help you
share what you discover
in a way that keeps
people interested.
After that, we'll move on to
the prepare step of the
data analysis process.
This is where data analysts
collect and store data
they'll use for the
upcoming analysis process.
You'll learn more about
the different types
of data and how to identify
which kinds of data are most
useful for solving a
particular problem.
You'll also discover why
it's so important that
your data and results are
objective and unbiased.
In other words, any decisions
made from your analysis
should always be based on
facts and be fair and impartial.
Next is the process step.
Here, data analysts
find and eliminate
any errors and inaccuracies
that can get in the
way of results.
This usually means cleaning data,
transforming it into a
more useful format,
combining two or more
datasets to make
information more complete
and removing outliers,
which are any data points that
could skew the information.
After that, you'll learn
how to check the data you
prepare to make sure it's
complete and correct.
This phase is all about
getting the details right.
So you'll also fix typos,
inconsistencies, or missing
and inaccurate data.
To top it off,
you'll gain strategies for
verifying and sharing
your data cleansing
with stakeholders.
Then it's time to analyze.
Analyzing the data
you've collected
involves using tools to transform
and organize that information
so that you can draw
useful conclusions,
make predictions, and drive
informed decision-making.
There are lots of powerful
tools data analysts use in
their work and in
this course you'll learn
about two of them,
spreadsheets and
structured query language,
or SQL, which is often
pronounced "sequel."
The next course is based
on the share phase.
Here you'll learn how
data analysts interpret
results and share them with
others to help stakeholders
make effective
data-driven decisions.
In the share phase,
visualization is a data
analyst's best friend.
So this course will highlight
why visualization is
essential to getting others to
understand what your
data is telling you.
With the right visuals,
facts and figures become
so much easier to
see and complex concepts
become easier to understand.
We'll explore different
kinds of visuals
and some great data
visualization tools.
You'll also practice
your own presentation
skills by creating
compelling slideshows
and learning
how to be fully prepared
to answer questions.
Then we'll take a break from
the data analysis process to
show you all of the really
cool things you can do with
the programming language
R. You don't need to be
familiar with R or programming
languages in general.
Just know that R is
a popular tool for
data manipulation, calculation,
and visualization.
For our final data analysis
phase, we have act.
This is the exciting moment when
the business takes all
of the insights you,
the data analyst, have
provided and puts them to
work in order to solve
the original business
problem and will be
acting on what you've learned
throughout this program.
This is when you prepare
for your job search
and have the chance to
complete a case study project.
It's a great opportunity
for you to bring together
everything you've worked
on throughout this course.
Plus adding a case study
to your portfolio helps you stand
out from the other
candidates when you
interview for your
first data analyst job.
Now you know the
different steps of
the data analysis process and
how our course reflects it.
You have everything you need
to understand how this course
works and my fellow Googlers and
I will be here to guide
you every step of the way.