Regardless of what type of
data analysis you're conducting,
the process is
generally the same.
The example that I'll
walk through is that
of our employee engagement
survey, but you could
imagine that this process
applies to just about
any data analysis that you're
going to conduct as an analyst.
The first thing you
want to do is ask.
You want to ask all of
the right questions at
the beginning of the
engagement so that
you better understand what
your leaders and stakeholders
need from this analysis.
The types of questions that
I generally ask are around,
what is the problem that
we're trying to solve?
What is the purpose
of this analysis?
What are we hoping
to learn from it?
After you've asked all the
right questions
and you've wrapped
your arms around the scope of
the analysis you need to conduct,
the next step is to prepare.
We need to be thinking
about what type of
data we need to answer
those key questions.
This could be anything from
quantitative data or
qualitative data.
It could be cross-sectional
or points in
time versus longitudinal
over a long period of time.
We need to be thinking
about the type of data
we need in order to
answer the questions
that we've set out
to answer based on
what we learned when we
asked the right questions.
We also need to be thinking about
how we're going to
collect that data
or if we need to
collect that data.
It may be the case that
we need to collect
this data brand-new.
So we need to think
about what type of
data we're going to be
collecting and how.
For our employee engagement survey,
we do that via survey of
both quantitative and
qualitative questions.
But it may actually be the
case that for many analyses,
the data that you're
looking for already exist.
Then it's a question of working
with those data
owners to make sure
that you are able to leverage
that data and use it responsibly.
After you've done all the hard
work to collect your data,
now you need to
process that data.
It begins with cleaning.
This to me is the most fun part
of the data analytics process.
We can think of it as
the initial introduction
or the handshake,
hello, to your data.
This is where you get a chance
to understand its structure,
its quirks, its nuances,
and you really get a
chance to understand
deeply what type of
data you're going to
be working with and understanding
what potential that data has
to answer all of your questions.
This is such an important
part, too,
where we're running
through all of
our quality assurance checks.
For example, do we have all of
the data that we
anticipated we would have?
Are we missing data at
random or is it missing in
a systematic way such that
maybe something went wrong with
our data collection effort?
If needed, did we code all
of our data the right way?
Are there any outliers that
we need to treat differently?
This is the part
where we spend a lot of
time really digging deeply into
the structure and nuance of
the data to make sure that
you're able to analyze
it appropriately
and responsibly.
After cleaning our
data and running
all of our quality
assurance checks,
now is the point where
we analyze our data,
making sure to do so in as
objective and unbiased
a way as possible.
To do this, the first
thing we do is run
through a series of
analyses that we've
already planned
ahead of time based
on the questions that we know we
want to answer from the very,
very beginning of the process.
One thing that's probably the
hardest about this
particular process,
the hardest thing
about analyzing data,
is that we as analysts are
trained to look for patterns.
Over time as we become better
and better at our jobs,
what we'll often find
is that we can start to
intuit what we might
see in the data.
We might have a
sneaking suspicion
as to what the data
are going to tell us.
This is the point where
we have to take a step
back and let the data
speak for itself.
As data analysts, we
are storytellers,
but we also have to
keep in mind that it
is not our story to tell.
That story belongs to the data,
and it is our job as
analysts to amplify and
tell that story in
as unbiased and objective
a way as possible.
The next step is to share
all of the data and
insights that you've
generated from your analyses.
Now typically for employee
engagement survey,
we start by sharing the
high-level findings
with our executive team.
We want them to have
a landscape view of
how the organization is feeling,
and we want to make sure
that there aren't
any surprises as they dig
deeper and deeper
into the data to
understand how teams are feeling
and how individual
employees are feeling.
All of this work
from asking the right questions
to collecting your data,
to analyzing and sharing,
doesn't mean much of anything
if we aren't taking action
on what we've just learned.
This to me is the
most critical part,
especially of our employee
engagement survey.
I like to say that the survey
is actually the easy part,
and acting on the results is
really where the
real work begins.
This is where we use all of
those data-driven insights to
decide what types of interventions
we want to introduce,
not only at the
organizational level,
but also at the
team level as well.
We might find, for example,
that the organization is
working on a series of
interventions to help improve
part of the employee experience,
whereas individual teams have
additional roles,
responsibilities to play,
to either bolster some of
those efforts or to introduce
new ones to better
meet their team
where their strengths and
opportunity areas are.
The data analysis
process is rigorous,
but it is lengthy.
I can completely appreciate
that we as data analysts,
get so excited about just
diving right into the data
and doing what we do best.
The challenge is that if we don't
work through the process
in its entirety,
if we try to skip steps,
we're not going to
be able to elicit
the insights that
we're looking for.
I absolutely love my job.
I have such a deep
appreciation for
data and what it can do and
what type of insight
we can derive from it.