Now that you know
the five essential
skills of a data analyst,
you're ready to learn more
about what it means to
think analytically.
People don't often
think about thinking.
Thinking is second nature to us.
It just happens automatically, but
there are actually many
different ways to think.
Some people think creatively,
some think critically,
and some people think
in abstract ways.
Let's talk about
analytical thinking.
Analytical thinking
involves identifying
and defining a problem and then
solving it by using data in
an organized, step-by-step manner.
As data analysts, how do
we think analytically?
Well, to answer that question,
we will now talk about
a second set of five.
The five key aspects to
analytical thinking.
They are visualization,
strategy, problem-orientation,
correlation, and finally,
big-picture and
detail-oriented thinking.
Let's start with visualization.
In data analytics, visualization
is the graphical
representation of information.
Some examples include graphs,
maps, or other design elements.
Visualization is important
because visuals can help
data analysts understand and
explain information
more effectively.
Think about it like this.
If you are trying to explain
the Grand Canyon to someone,
using words would be much
more challenging than
showing them a picture.
A visualization of the
Grand Canyon would
help you make your
point much quicker.
Now let's talk about
the second part of
analytical thinking,
being strategic.
With so much data available,
having a strategic mindset is
key to staying
focused and on track.
Strategizing helps data
analysts see what they
want to achieve with the data
and how they can get there.
Strategy also helps improve
the quality and usefulness
of the data we collect.
By strategizing, we
know all our data is
valuable and can help us
accomplish our goals.
Next step on the analytical
thinking checklist:
being problem-oriented.
Data analysts use a problem-
oriented approach in
order to identify,
describe, and solve problems.
It's all about keeping
the problem top of
mind throughout the
entire project.
For example, say a data
analyst is told about
the problem of a warehouse
constantly running
out of supplies.
They would move forward with
different strategies
and processes.
But the number one
goal would always be
solving the problem of keeping
inventory on the shelves.
Data analysts also ask
a lot of questions.
This helps improve
communication and
saves time while
working on a solution.
An example of that would be
surveying customers about
their experiences
using a product and
building insights from
those questions to
improve their product.
This leads us to
the fourth quality
of analytical thinking:
being able to identify
a correlation between two
or more pieces of data.
A correlation is
like a relationship.
You can find all kinds
of correlations in data.
Maybe it's the relationship
between the length of
your hair and the amount
of shampoo you need.
Or maybe you notice a
correlation between
a rainier season leading to
a high number of
umbrellas being sold.
But as you start identifying
correlations in data,
there's one thing you always
want to keep in mind:
Correlation does not
equal causation.
In other words, just
because two pieces of
data are both trending
in the same direction,
that doesn't necessarily
mean they are all related.
We'll learn more
about that later.
Now the final piece of
the analytical thinking
puzzle: big-picture thinking.
This means being able to see
the big picture as
well as the details.
A jigsaw puzzle is a great
way to think about this.
Big-picture thinking is like
looking at a complete puzzle.
You can enjoy the
whole picture without
getting stuck on every tiny
piece that went into making it.
If you only focus on
individual pieces,
you wouldn't be able
to see past that,
which is why big-picture
thinking is so important.
It helps you zoom out and
see possibilities
and opportunities.
This leads to exciting
new ideas or innovations.
On the flip side, detail-oriented
thinking is all about
figuring out all of the aspects
that will help you
execute a plan.
In other words, the pieces
that make up your puzzle.
There are all kinds
of problems in
the business world
that can benefit from
employees who have
both a big-picture
and a detail-oriented
way of thinking.
Most of us are naturally
better at one or the other.
But you can always develop
the skills to fit
both pieces together.
Now that you know
the five aspects
of analytical thinking,
visualization, strategy,
problem-orientation,
correlation, and
big-picture and
detail-oriented thinking,
you can put them to work for
you when you're
working with data.
As you continue through this
course, you'll learn how.