Let's recap what we've learned
about analytical thinking so far.
The 5 key aspects are
visualization, strategy,
problem-orientation,
correlation, and
using big-picture
and detail-oriented thinking.
We've seen how you already
use them in your everyday life.
We also talked about
how different people
naturally use certain
types of thinking,
but that you can absolutely
grow and develop
the skills that might not
come as easily to you.
This means you can become
a versatile thinker,
which is a very important
part of data analysis.
You might naturally be
an analytical thinker,
but you can learn to
think creatively
and critically, and be
great at all three.
The more ways you can think,
the easier it is to think outside
the box and come up
with fresh ideas.
But why is it important to
think in different ways?
Well because in data
analysis, solutions
are almost never right
in front of you.
You need to think critically to
find out the right
questions to ask.
But you also need
to think creatively
to get new and
unexpected answers.
Let's talk about some
of the questions data
analysts ask when they're on
the hunt for a solution.
Here's one that
will come up a lot:
What is the root
cause of a problem?
A root cause is the reason
why a problem occurs.
If we can identify and
get rid of a root cause,
we can prevent that problem
from happening again.
A simple way to wrap
your head around
root causes is with the
process called the Five Whys.
In the Five Whys you ask
"why" five times to
reveal the root cause.
The fifth and final
answer should give you
some useful and sometimes
surprising insights.
Here's an example of the
Five Whys in action.
Let's say you wanted to make
a blueberry pie but couldn't
find any blueberries.
You've been trying to
solve a problem by asking,
why can't I make a blueberry pie?
The answer will be, there
are no blueberries at the store.
There's Why Number 1.
You then ask, why were there
no blueberries at the store?
Then you discover that the
blueberry bushes
don't have enough
fruit this season.
That's Why Number 2.
Next, you'd ask, why was
there not enough fruit?
This would lead to the fact that
birds were eating
all the berries.
Why Number 3, asked and answered.
Now we get to Why Number 4.
Ask why a fourth time and
the answer would be that,
although the birds
normally prefer
mulberries and don't
eat blueberries,
the mulberry bush didn't
produce fruit this season,
so the birds are eating
blueberries instead.
Finally, we get to Why Number 5,
which should reveal
the root cause.
A late frost damaged
the mulberry bushes,
so it didn't produce any fruit.
You can't make a blueberry pie
because of the late
frost months ago.
See how the Five Whys can reveal
some very surprising root causes.
This is a great trick
to know, and it can be
a very helpful process
in data analysis.
Another question commonly
asked by data analysts is,
where are the gaps
in our process?
For this, many people will use
something called gap analysis.
Gap analysis lets you examine
and evaluate how a process
works currently in order
to get where you want
to be in the future.
Businesses conduct gap analysis
to do all kinds of things,
such as improve a product
or become more efficient.
The general approach
to gap analysis is
understanding where you are now
compared to where you want to be.
Then you can identify the
gaps that exist between
the current and future state
and determine how to bridge them.
A third question that data
analysts ask a lot is,
what did we not consider before?
This is a great way to think
about what information
or procedure might be
missing from a process,
so you can identify ways to make
better decisions and
strategies moving forward.
These are just a few
examples of the kinds of
questions data analysts
use at their jobs every day.
As you begin your career,
I'm sure you'll think
of a whole lot more.
The way data analysts
think and ask questions
plays a big part in how
businesses make decisions.
That's why analytical thinking
and understanding how to ask
the right questions can have
such a huge impact on the
overall success of a business.
Later, we'll talk more
about how data-driven
decisions can lead to
successful outcomes.