Hi, again. I'm glad you're back.
In this part of the program,
we'll revisit the spreadsheet.
Spreadsheets are a powerful
and versatile tool,
which is why they're
a big part of
pretty much everything
we do as data analysts.
There's a good chance a
spreadsheet will
be the first tool
you reach for when trying
to answer data-driven questions.
After you've defined what you
need to do with the data,
you'll turn to
spreadsheets to help
build evidence that you
can then visualize,
and use to support your findings.
Spreadsheets are often
the unsung heroes
of the data world.
They don't always get the
appreciation they deserve,
but as a data detective,
you'll definitely want them in
your evidence collection kit.
I know spreadsheets have saved
the day for me more than once.
I've added data for purchase
orders into a sheet,
setup formulas in one tab,
and had the same formulas do
the work for me in other tabs.
This frees up time for me to work
on other things during the day.
I couldn't imagine not
using spreadsheets.
Math is a core part of
every data analyst's job,
but not every analyst enjoys it.
Luckily, spreadsheets can make
calculations more enjoyable,
and by that, I mean
easier. Let's see how.
Spreadsheets can do
both basic and complex
calculations automatically.
Not only does this help you
work more efficiently,
but it also lets you see
the results and understand
how you got them.
Here's a quick look at some of
the functions that you'll
use when performing calculations.
Many functions can be used as
part of a math formula as well.
Functions and formulas
also have other uses,
and we'll take a
look at those too.
We'll take things one
step further with
exercises that use real
data from databases.
This is your chance to
reorganize a spreadsheet,
do some actual data analysis,
and have some fun with data.