Hey. It's great to have you back.
We've talked a little bit about
the data analysis process.
As a quick refresher,
the data analysis process phases
are ask, prepare, process,
analyze, share, and act.
You might remember
me saying earlier
that this entire program is
modeled after these steps.
Now, we're going
to really dig in
and explore how each of
these phases work together.
But I'm getting a
little ahead of myself.
First, let's spend a little time
understanding the data life cycle.
No, data isn't actually alive,
but it does have a life cycle.
How do data analysts
bring data to life?
Well, it starts with the
right data analysis tool.
These include
spreadsheets, databases,
query languages, and
visualization software.
Don't worry if you don't
know how these work,
or even what they are.
At one point, every data analyst
has been right where
you are right now,
and they probably had a
lot of the same questions.
I remember when I first started
learning about spreadsheets.
I was a young intern,
and the company I
was working for
was in the middle of
a big systems change.
That meant, we had
to move tons of
reports from the old
system to the new one.
After a few weeks,
I noticed that even the people
who were further
in their careers
were not as technically
minded as I was.
That became a great opportunity
for me to add value.
My aha spreadsheet moment
came when I started
researching shortcuts
that I could use to work with
the spreadsheets
more efficiently.
This would really
streamline the process of
getting those reports moved
over to the new system.
Once everything started flowing,
I remember getting emails from
other finance analysts
at the company.
They were so grateful
that someone had come in
and fixed a problem
that no one else could.
That inspired me to
go even further
and learn how to
use spreadsheets
in all sorts of incredible ways.
As you continue
through this course,
I bet you'll be just
as impressed as I was.
And before you know
it, you'll bring data
to life too. Let's get started.