Welcome back. Now it's time to
go even further and
build on what you've
learned about problem-solving in
data analytics and crafting
effective questions.
Coming up, we'll cover
a wide range of topics.
You'll learn about
how data can empower
our decisions, big and small;
the difference between
quantitative and
qualitative analysis
and when to use them;
the pros and cons of different
data visualization tools;
what metrics are, and
how analysts use them;
and how to use mathematical
thinking to connect the dots.
To be honest, I'm still learning
more about these
things every day,
and so will you! Like how
quantitative and qualitative
data can work together.
In my role in finance,
most of my work is quantitative,
but recently I was working
on a project that focused
a lot on empathy and trust
and that was really new for me.
But we took those more
qualitative things
into account during analysis,
and that really helped
me understand how
quantitative and
qualitative data can come
together to help us make
powerful decisions.
Now you're on your
way to building
your own data analyst toolkit.
Before you know it,
you'll be analyzing
all kinds of data
yourself and learning new
things while you do it.
But first, let's start
small with the power
of observation.